mlcalc.com 2019-06-02

# Privacy Policy

**By visiting, using and/or submitting information to[www.mlcalc.com (Mortgage Calculator)](https://www.mlcalc.com/) (the “Site”), you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy and the terms and conditions of the Site’s Agreement of Terms of Use located at the URL <https://www.mlcalc.com/terms.htm> (the “Terms of Use”).  **

This Privacy Policy explains the use of information you may submit to the Site, except that information which is submitted pursuant to a sweepstakes entry. Refer to the Official Rules and Privacy Policy for each individual sweepstakes for specific policies regarding information sharing and disclosure pursuant to sweepstakes entry. 

**Collection of Personally Identifiable Information**

Many of the features of the Site are available to you without your providing personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information generally includes information that could be used to determine your identity, such as your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and birth date.  The following are certain situations in which your personally identifiable information may be collected:

  * **Registration for Newsletters and Sweepstakes.**   Your personally identifiable information will be collected if you register online for newsletters and when you enter sweepstakes. When you register online, you will be asked for personally identifiable information like your name, e-mail address, birth date, gender, ZIP code, occupation, industry, personal interests and other demographic information. 
  * **Use of Forums.  ** If you choose to transmit, submit or post information through  chat rooms, bulletin boards or other forums (the “Forums”), any information provided by you will be collected.  This information will be retained as necessary to resolve disputes, provide customer support and troubleshoot problems as permitted by law and pursuant to the Site’s Terms of Use. 
  * **Forms.   **Personally identifiable information may be collected from you if you choose to fill out any forms, profiles, or surveys on the Site. 
  * **Correspondence.  ** If you send personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site, any information provided may be collected into a file specific to you. 
  * **Business Partners.** Your personally identifiable information may be received from one of the Site’s business partners. 

**Use of Personally Identifiable Information**

Your personally identifiable information will be used as follows: 

  * to improve the Site’s marketing and promotional efforts, analyze site usage, improve the Site’s content and product offerings, and customize the Site 's content, layout, and services; 
  * to contact you and deliver information to you that, in some cases, is targeted to your interests, such as targeted banner advertisements, administrative notices, product offerings, and communications relevant to your use of  the Site; 
  * to fulfill your requests for certain products and services; 
  * for market research, project planning, troubleshooting problems, detecting and protecting against error, fraud or other criminal activity, to enforce the Site’s Terms of Use, for other internal purposes, and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection; and 
  * as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

You expressly agree to the Site's use of your personally identifiable information as set forth in this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use.

**Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information**

Unless you are entering a sweepstakes, your personally identifiable information will not be sold.  The following describes some of the ways that your personally identifiable information may be disclosed in the normal scope of business:

  * **Advertisers.**   Personally identifiable information may be aggregated and disclosed in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for their marketing and promotional purposes.  For example, personally identifiable information may be aggregated and disclosed to network advertisers in a non-personally identifiable manner as set forth in the section entitled "Network Advertisers," set forth below. Your information will not be disclosed in a personally identifiable manner to such third party advertisers without your consent. 
  * **External Service Providers.**   There are a number of separate services offered by affiliates and third parties that are referred to as external service providers that may be complementary to your use of the Site (e.g. realtors, mortgage brokers, lenders, financial institutions, credit card issuers, information aggregators).  If you choose to use these separate services, disclose information to the external service providers, and/or grant them permission to collect information about you, then their use of your information is governed by their privacy policy.  With your consent, some of your personal information may be provided to the external service provider offering such services, for your convenience.  To prevent  disclosure of your personally identifiable information to an external service provider, you can decline such consent or simply not use their services.  You should evaluate the practices of external services providers before deciding to use their services. 
  * **Internal Service Providers.  ** Third parties, referred to as internal service providers, may be used to facilitate or outsource one or more aspects of  the Site's business, or products and services provided to you (e.g., technology, Forums, newsletters/alerts, analytical tools, advertising campaign management) and therefore some of your personal information may be provided directly to these internal service providers.  These internal service providers are subject to confidentiality agreements or other legal restrictions that prohibit their use of the information provided to them for any other purpose except to facilitate the specific outsourced related operation, unless you have explicitly agreed or given your prior permission to them for additional uses.  In some instances, the internal service provider may collect information directly from you.  In these cases, you will be notified of the involvement of the internal service provider, and all additional information you provide them and their additional uses will be strictly up to you.  If you provide additional information to an internal service provider directly, then their use of your personally identifiable information is governed by their applicable privacy policy. 

Notwithstanding the foregoing, the right to share or disclose your personally identifiable information is hereby reserved when it is determined that the disclosure of your personally identifiable information is, determined in our sole discretion, to be necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against you if:

  * you are or may be violating this Privacy Policy or the Site’s Terms of Use; 
  * you are interfering with another's rights or property; 
  * you are violating any applicable law, rule or regulation; 
  * necessary or required by any applicable law, rule or regulation; and/or 
  * requested by authorities in the event of any act of terrorism or instance of local, regional or national emergency. 

You hereby authorize the release of your personally identifiable information in the foregoing cases.

Personally identifiable information and other personal information collected from you may also be transferred to a third party as a result of a sale, acquisition, merger, reorganization, other transfer or bankruptcy (a “Transfer”).  The right to transfer personally identifiable information collected from the Site, and any of its databases, together with any personally identifiable information contained therein, to a third party in connection with a Transfer is hereby reserved, and nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to interfere with the ability to transfer all or part of the business and/or assets (including the Site) to an affiliate or independent third party at any time, for any purpose, without any limitation whatsoever.

In addition, due to the existing regulatory environment, there is no assurance that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.  By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), personal information may have to be disclosed to the government or third parties under certain circumstances or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications.  Therefore, although industry standard practices are used to protect your privacy, it cannot be promised, and you should not expect, that your personally identifiable information or private communications will always remain private.

**NOTE:** If you are submitting personally identifiable information pursuant to sweepstakes entry, the right to share, loan, rent and/or sell the personally identifiable information that you submit with affiliates and other third parties is hereby reserved. Please refer to the Official Rules and Privacy Policy for each individual sweepstakes for the specific guidelines regarding information sharing and disclosure.

**Network Advertising**

Third-party advertising companies may be used for marketing, advertising and promotional purposes, as well as to serve advertisements to you.  Using third-party advertising companies helps us and third-party advertisers better determine which advertisements or content to serve to you.  For example, the third-party advertisers may use information regarding your visits to the Site and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services, that third party advertisers believe will be of interest to you. 

The types of information that may be collected by third-party advertising companies include the following: 

  * the type of Internet browser you use; 
  * the type of computer operating system you use; 
  * the domain name of a Web site you visit, as well as information related to Web sites and Web pages you are viewing when an advertisement is requested; 
  * whether or not you visit specific pages of the Site or other Web sites; 
  * the location of your Internet service provider's point of presence; 
  * the date and time of a visit to a Web site; 
  * search keywords passed from another server; 
  * the number of times you have clicked on an advertisement; and 
  * other interactions between you and a Web site. 

**Newsletters and CAN-SPAM Compliance**

We will only send verified, double-opt-in e-mail newsletters, specifically requested by subscribers. Subscriptions to newsletters are verified by sending an e-mail confirmation to your e-mail address, which requires a positive response before an e-mail address is added to a subscriber list. 

**Cookie technology**

"Cookies" are alphanumeric identifiers in the form of text files that are inserted and stored by your Web browser on your computer's hard drive. The Site, its external service providers, internal service providers, and third-party advertising companies, may set and access cookies on your computer to track and store preferential information about you. The Site, and its external service providers, internal service providers, and third-party advertising companies gather anonymous information about you through cookie technology on an aggregate level only. For example, a third-party advertising company may assign a cookie (and a Web beacon, described below) to you, to limit the amount of times you see a particular advertisement or to help better determine which advertisements to serve to you.  Please note that most Internet browsers will allow you to stop cookies from being stored on your computer and to delete cookies stored on your computer.

**Web beacons**

”Web beacons”, also called single-pixels (1x1) or clear GIFs, are electronic images that allow a Web site to access cookies and help track marketing campaigns and general usage patterns of visitors to those Web sites.   Web beacons can recognize certain types of information, such as cookie numbers, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed.  No personally identifiable information about you is shared with third parties through the use of Web beacons. 

  * **Internal use of Web beacons.**   Web beacons may be used internally to count users and recognize users through cookies.  Access to cookies helps personalize your experience when you visit the Site. 
  * **Email.**   Web beacons may be included in HTML-formatted email messages that are sent.  Including Web beacons in email messages helps determine your interest in and the effectiveness of such emails. 
  * **External use of Web beacons.**   Web beacons may also be used externally.  For example, aggregate information about the Site’s users, such as demographic and usage information, may be reported to partners and other third parties.  Other company’s Web beacons may also be used within the Site. 

**Security**

Personally identifiable information you submit is password-protected for your privacy and security. In certain areas, industry-standard SSL-encryption is used to protect data transmissions. In the unlikely event that an unauthorized third party compromises security measures, you agree not to hold any affiliate of the Site responsible for any damages directly or indirectly caused by an unauthorized third party's ability to view, use or disseminate such information.

**Links to Other Web sites**

The Site may include links to other third party Web sites. Such links are not an endorsement of those Web sites and/or the products or services offered there. Third party Web sites may have different privacy policies and, therefore, no responsibility for the privacy practices of those third party Web sites is assumed. If you click on a link to a third party Web site, you are encouraged to check the privacy policy of that Web site, as it may differ substantially from that of this Privacy Policy.

**Access and Use of the Site**

The Site is intended to be accessed and used only by adults and is not directed to children under the age of 18. Registration or submission of personally identifiable information by anyone under the age of 18 will not be knowingly permitted.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

The right to update, amend and/or change this Privacy Policy at any time and without notice is reserved. Updates to this Privacy Policy will be posted here. Any information collected from you online is subject only to the Site’s most current Privacy Policy. You are encouraged to revisit this Privacy Policy from time to time in order to review any changes that have been made. Your continued access and use of the Site following the posting of any such changes shall automatically be deemed your acceptance of the same.

**Questions or Concerns**

If you have questions, comments, concerns or feedback regarding this Privacy Policy, [contact us](https://www.mlcalc.com/feedback.htm).

**Miscellaneous**

If any portion of this Privacy Policy is deemed unlawful, void or unenforceable by any arbitrator, this Privacy Policy as a whole shall not be deemed unlawful, void or unenforceable, but only that portion of this Privacy Policy that is unlawful, void or unenforceable shall be stricken from this Privacy Policy.

The headings contained in this Privacy Policy are for convenience of reference only, are not to be considered a part of this Privacy Policy, and shall not limit or otherwise affect in any way the meaning or interpretation of this Privacy Policy.

All covenants, agreements, representations and warranties made in this Privacy Policy, as may be amended from time to time, shall survive your acceptance of this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use represent the entire understanding and agreement regarding the subject matter of the same, and supersede all other previous agreements, understandings and/or representations regarding the same.
